NANWARIN CHANTARUTAI

Pomona, CA | 562-331-8005 | nchantarutai@cpp.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nanwarin

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 4 years of automatic test scripts with Java and Linux. **Web developer with 2 years** of web service projects with Java, Spring Boot, Servlet, Python, Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AngularJS, MongoDB, MySQL and AWS. Have keen **interest** in clean software designs, agile development cycle and creating software applications to reduce routine activities.

EDUCATION

Master of Science: Computer Science

California State Polytechnic University - Pomona Major GPA 3.85, Cumulative GPA 3.69.

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

Pomona, CA

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

Suranaree University of Technology Recipient of University Scholarship. May 2007 - Dec 2010

Thailand

WORK EXPERIENCE

Website Developer

California State Polytechnic University – Pomona

Apr 2016 - Current

Pomona, CA

 Design and develop on both backend and frontend for web service projects including Housing Cost Calculator and Custom CMS. (Java, Spring Boot, HTML5, JavaScript, AngularJS, CSS3, MySQL, JSoup)

Research Assistant Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

California State Polytechnic University – Pomona

Pomona, CA

 Worked with Dr. Abellera Lourdes and another research assistant. Researched and developed data analysis application on negative comments from Twitter in order to identify negative influencers that mislead information about California Public Transportation. This project was funded by Caltrans. (Java, Twitter API, JSON, Machine Learning)

Software Engineer Feb 2011 - Dec 2015

Western Digital Corporation

Thailand

- Intracompany transferred to work at headquarters in Irvine, CA for 1 year. Created automatic test scripts for products under development and worked on Hydra Project with the development team. (Java, SVN, XML, Linux)
- Developed and modified automatic test scripts for production products. Performed debugging and troubleshooting on test scripts and testers. (Java, SVN, Bus Analyzer, Linux)
- Developed Log Reader and Test Submission web services projects that reduces routine activities. Gained 80% reduction of working time. (Java, Servlets, HTML, JavaScript)

Intern Feb 2011 - Dec 2015

Western Digital Corporation

Thailand

Developed a web service project to virtualize data that reduce data retrieval and graph plotting times from 30 minutes to 5 minutes. (Java, Subversion, XML, Linux)

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Fake News Detection Apr 2017 – May 2017

Group project with 5 grad students for Machine Learning class. Developed a feature extraction function for preprocessing process in order to create a better training dataset. (Python, Scikit-learn, Spacy, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning)

Q-BOT IO Jan 2017 – Feb 2017

Back-end developer for an IR Closed-Domain Answering System that generates relevant and accurate answers to Computer Science Interview questions. Worked together with grad 4 students by applying agile software development process. (Python, NLTK, Django, MongoDB, Elastic Search, Information Retrieval, Natural Language Processing)

Bronco-Planner CPP Student Organizer

Jan 2017 – Feb 2017

Project manager of a Restful web service project with 3 grad students by applying agile software development process. Lead, plan, and design the organizer that suggests events, activities, workshops, and fitness classes based on student's class schedule. (Java, Spring Boot, JSoup, JUnit, AngularJS, HTML, MongoDB, JQuery, AWS EC2, JSON)

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

Languages:Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3Tools:Linux, Spring Boot, AWS EC2, JSON, Git